<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Jamikal Hall - Blue Teamer</title>
    <link>/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Jamikal Hall - Blue Teamer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 10:08:47 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Linux Basics For Hackers Notes: Chapter 1</title>
      <link>/posts/lb4h1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 10:08:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/lb4h1/</guid>
      <description>I originally wrote this a year ago on Medium. I have gone through these steps again, but I am trying ParrotOS instead of Kali. I did this to gain experience with a different distribution and in case I want to do exercises on HTB.
Linux Basics for Hackers Notes: Chapter 1
The first thing I did for this was set up my Kali Linux VM. I downloaded Oracle’s VM box and set it up according to the instructions in the book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Pipeline Automation</title>
      <link>/posts/intro-to-pipelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 10:03:48 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/intro-to-pipelines/</guid>
      <description>In my last post, I built a simple pipeline to automatically update my website whenever I make a push to my Git repository. In this post, I am posting the notes I have taken from TryHackMe&amp;rsquo;s room on pipeline automation. I am not going to copy verbatim, rather summarize the notes in my own words.
Learning Objectives
This room will teach you about the following concepts:
 Introduction to the DevOps pipeline Introduction to DevOps tools and automation Introduction to security principles for the DevOps pipeline  A pipeline likely consists of the following:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a CI/CD Pipeline with Hugo</title>
      <link>/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 10:23:27 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>I do not particularly like front-end development. I don&amp;rsquo;t hate it, but I find building systems and working on the backend to be far more interesting. When working on the Cloud Resume Challenge, a lot of it is contingent on having a front-end for viewers to see.
I decided that I want to be able to work on the later stages of the challenges, but not have to build an entire blog from scratch.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
