<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Jamikal Hall - Blue Teamer</title>
    <link>/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Jamikal Hall - Blue Teamer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 11:48:54 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing Threats and Building Detection Rules</title>
      <link>/posts/soc-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 11:48:54 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/soc-analysis/</guid>
      <description>In this lab, I wanted to hone my skills and conduct a SOC investigation starting from scratch, setting up every aspect and attacking the VMs I deploy to gain a better understanding of how SOCs work. This lab is from Eric Cupuano and I am following his steps so this would not be possible without him. As a security analyst, I expect that one of the most important parts of the job is to detect suspicous activities, mitigate them, then create rules (and also fine-tune them) so that similar attacks cannot happen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investigating Malware with OpenCTI</title>
      <link>/posts/open-cti-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 11:48:54 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/open-cti-1/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I document how I used OpenCTI, an open-source threat intelligence platform to investigate malware.
&amp;ldquo;As a SOC analyst, you have been tasked with investigations on malware and APT groups rampaging through the world. Your assignment is to look into the CaddyWiper malware and APT37 group. Gather information from OpenCTI to answer the following questions.&amp;quot;
Question 1: What is the earliest date recorded related to CaddyWiper? Format: YYYY/MM/DD</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Containers</title>
      <link>/posts/containers-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 18:23:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/containers-intro/</guid>
      <description>Learning Outcomes:
By completing this room, you will know:
 What containerisation is and what containers are Where and why containerization is used? A fundamental understanding of the popular containerisation technology called Docker What makes Docker so popular How containerization works  What is Containerization? Basically, containerization is the process of packaging an application and all of its necessary resource such as libraries, packages, and dependencies into one package named a container.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Cybersecurity with OverTheWire: Bandit 1 - 5</title>
      <link>/posts/bandit1-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 11:02:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/bandit1-5/</guid>
      <description>I stumbled across this repository of wargames called OverTheWire. They teach cybersecurity concepts through a gaming like method, and I love games so this seemed like a good place to start. This was highly recommended on reddit so I am documenting my path through the wargames, including difficulties I faced.
OverTheWire recommends starting with Bandit, so I grab a cup of Death Wish Coffee and get to work!
Bandit Level 0 Level Goal: The goal of this level is for you to log into the game using SSH.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux Basics For Hackers Notes: Chapter 1</title>
      <link>/posts/lb4h1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 10:08:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/lb4h1/</guid>
      <description>I originally wrote this a year ago on Medium. I have gone through these steps again, but I am trying ParrotOS instead of Kali. I did this to gain experience with a different distribution and in case I want to do exercises on HTB.
Linux Basics for Hackers Notes: Chapter 1
The first thing I did for this was set up my Kali Linux VM. I downloaded Oracle’s VM box and set it up according to the instructions in the book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Pipeline Automation</title>
      <link>/posts/intro-to-pipelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 10:03:48 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/intro-to-pipelines/</guid>
      <description>In my last post, I built a simple pipeline to automatically update my website whenever I make a push to my Git repository. In this post, I am posting the notes I have taken from TryHackMe&amp;rsquo;s room on pipeline automation. I am not going to copy verbatim, rather summarize the notes in my own words.
Learning Objectives
This room will teach you about the following concepts:
 Introduction to the DevOps pipeline Introduction to DevOps tools and automation Introduction to security principles for the DevOps pipeline  A pipeline likely consists of the following:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a CI/CD Pipeline with Hugo</title>
      <link>/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 10:23:27 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to do part of the Cloud Resume Challenge.
I decided that I want to be able to work on the later stages of the challenges, but not have to build an entire blog from scratch. I knew I needed to host it myself in an S3 bucket as a static site. I had also been interested in learning a programming language really well, and had several debates between learning Python and Go.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
