<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Jamikal Hall - Blue Teamer</title>
    <link>/tags/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Jamikal Hall - Blue Teamer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 11:48:54 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing Threats and Building Detection Rules</title>
      <link>/posts/soc-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 11:48:54 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/soc-analysis/</guid>
      <description>In this lab, I wanted to hone my skills and conduct a SOC investigation starting from scratch, setting up every aspect and attacking the VMs I deploy to gain a better understanding of how SOCs work. This lab is from Eric Cupuano and I am following his steps so this would not be possible without him. As a security analyst, I expect that one of the most important parts of the job is to detect suspicous activities, mitigate them, then create rules (and also fine-tune them) so that similar attacks cannot happen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investigating Malware with OpenCTI</title>
      <link>/posts/open-cti-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 11:48:54 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/open-cti-1/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I document how I used OpenCTI, an open-source threat intelligence platform to investigate malware.
&amp;ldquo;As a SOC analyst, you have been tasked with investigations on malware and APT groups rampaging through the world. Your assignment is to look into the CaddyWiper malware and APT37 group. Gather information from OpenCTI to answer the following questions.&amp;quot;
Question 1: What is the earliest date recorded related to CaddyWiper? Format: YYYY/MM/DD</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a CI/CD Pipeline with Hugo</title>
      <link>/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 10:23:27 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to do part of the Cloud Resume Challenge.
I decided that I want to be able to work on the later stages of the challenges, but not have to build an entire blog from scratch. I knew I needed to host it myself in an S3 bucket as a static site. I had also been interested in learning a programming language really well, and had several debates between learning Python and Go.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
